

# LADY CATHERINE MARIN H - QA ENGINEER

+356 99160698 | lady.marin@cun.edu.co | Linkedin.com/in/ladycmarinh

Country of residence: Malta Nationality: Colombian

#### **Profile**

Professional in Systems Engineering, with 6 years of experience in planning, design and execution of software functional tests, knowledge of the Scrum framework, basic SQL database queries, JIRA, basic automated test in Cypress and experience in the banking sector.

## Work Experiences

#### Leah App S.A.S - Bogotá, Colombia (Remote)

Feb 2022 - Apr 2024

QA Engineer

- Planning and execution of quality tests on web and mobile applications.
- Creation of test cases taking into account alternate flows.
- Execution of scripts and basic knowledge of automated tests in Cypress.
- · Identification and documentation of problems and defects in the systems using the Jira tool.
- Collaboration with the development team to solve problems and ensure that the products meet the requirements and specifications.
- Use agile methodologies (SCRUM) to work on software projects.

### Tata Consultancy Services - Bogotá, Colombia (Remote)

Jun 2018 - Jan 2022

Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

Analyst Functional Testing

- · Planning and execution of functional tests.
- · Requirements analysis and review of product documentation specifications to ensure compliance with quality standards and industry best practices.
- Monitoring and tracking of software quality throughout the project life cycle.
- Test case development and documentation.
- SQL database management to perform basic queries.
- · ALM management to track the project.
- Identification of areas of improvement and proposing solutions to optimize the testing process and ensure product quality.
- · Generation of detailed reports on test results.
- knowledge of applications in the banking sector

#### **Education Level**

CUN National Unified Corporation of Higher Education - Bogotá, Colombia  Diploma in Systems Engineering	Jan 2012 - Apr 2017
CUN National Unified Corporation of Higher Education - Bogotá, Colombia  Diploma in Project Management aligned with PMI methodology	Jul 2016 - Dec 2016
CUN National Unified Corporation of Higher Education - Bogotá, Colombia  Diploma in Network Routing and Switching (Cisco)	Jul 2015 - Dec 2015
Triangle Institute - Bogotá, Colombia Undergraduate in Computer and Systems Technician	Jan 2011 - Dec 2012
Certifications	
Pushing IT – (Virtual) Argentina Certificate in Cypress Automation	May 2023 - Aug 2023
Certmind - Bogotá, Colombia Certificate in Scrum Master	Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

## Skills, Achievements & Other Experience

- Hard Skills: Jira, Scrum, ALM, Cypress, SQL, Postman, MS Office
- Soft Skills: Fast learning, Communicative, Problem solving, Critical & analytical thinking
- Languages: English-A2, Spanish-Native

Certmind - Bogotá, Colombia

Certificate in Scrum Fundamentals